JACK MICHAUD

Full Stack Engineer

@ jack@lomz.me

Seattle, WA

in linkedin.com/in/jack-michaud

github.com/jack-michaud

I am full stack engineer with experience in making secure infrastructure and writing scalable systems. My mission is to write clean, reliable, and resilient code and grow in a fast paced environment. In a leadership position, I lead by example and elevate the best qualities in my teammates.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Engineer

Knock (knockcrm.com)

🛗 Jun 2020 - Present

- Hacked on CRM application with legacy Python 2 and AngularJS (developed plans to modernization into Python 3 microservices).
- Designed, planned, wrote, and deployed scalable email service. Handled 5+ GB of data per minute with 0 downtime since launching in November 2021
- Created canary Terraform module for safely launching changes to test with production traffic
- Developed system design documents guiding company-wide efforts for modern Terraform and Jenkins deployments (and adopting the canary module).
- Reviewed technical designs from throughout the org.

Full Stack Engineer

Metascouter, Inc (metascouter.gg)

May 2018 - Jun 2020

♀ (Remote) Seattle. WA

- Constructed APIs (REST, GraphQL) and broadcast graphics (ReactJS) for integrating data into major esports broadcasts.
- Designed and developed full stack infrastructure while coordinating with remote team.
- Created real-time data pipeline using MQTT, Protobuf, and queueing to ingest data from computer vision software. (Deployed with CloudFormation).
- Implemented serverless AWS architecture with DynamoDB, Lambda, and API gateway with GraphQL interface.
- Carried out growth marketing experiments with AdWords and Google Analytics.
- Started closed beta engaging with 5 end users actively using our product.
- Released 1.0 software after iterating on feedback.

Software Development Co-Op

Solaria Labs (solarialabs.com)

🛗 Jul 2018 - Dec 2018

♀ Boston, MA

- Implemented serverless AWS data pipeline and generic CloudFormation template generation.
- Collaborated actively with 2-3 teams writing Python and JS backend code, JS frontend, building CI pipelines, and integrating said data pipeline.
- Evaluated open source and commercial business data on location data for reliability against ground truth.

Founding Partner

Harrow Search (harrowsearch.com)

m Oct 2015 - Jul 2019

- Established LLC for a website that displays analytics from data scraped from YouTube, Twitter, Facebook, and Instagram.
- Created web application stack with Django, ReactJS, Selenium, and Docker.
 Implemented CI/CD in Gitlab.
- Supervised and directed three temporary contractors.

EDUCATION

Northeastern University

B.S. in Computer Science

Graduated: May 2020

- Networking and Distributed Systems: Implemented custom distributed systems like Raft and a custom TCP implementation
- Software Development: Developing software usinsg engineering best practices (SRS documents, Scrum/Agile, testing)
- Large Scale Parallel Data Processing: Learned to design efficient algorithms in Hadoop and Spark
- Systems Security: Learned to mitigate operating system security in embedded, mobile, and desktop devices (RBAC, secure execution, chain of trust)

RELEVANT SKILLS

Languages

Python TypeScript/JavaScript
Golang Rust Java

Tools

Terraform Docker

CI/CD (Jenkins, CircleCI, Bamboo, Gitlab)

Vim Emacs GNU/Linux

Skills In Development

Interplanetary Filesystem (IPFS)

Nix

INTERESTS/ACTIVITIES

Coach for Collegiate Cyber Defence Club (CCDC)

Self-hosted services and home lab

□ DJing and Music Production

Hiking

PROJECTS

Ephemeral Server (2021)

https://github.com/jack-michaud/ephemeral-server

- A Go Discord bot used to manage a self hosted Minecraft servers for asneeded hosting
- Uses Ansible and Terraform to provision and configure servers
- CI/CD with Semantic Release and multi-architecture docker builds

"Hoobastank" Data Collection (2021)

https://git.xskj.org/jack/hoobastank (Private)

- A Go program for data collection from UDP telemetry
- Collects telemetry data from Forza Horizon 5 and F1 (2021)
- Dockerized and deployed for private use with docker compose

Washington State Academy of Audiology (2020)

https://washingtonaudiology.org

- A JAMStack website built for my partner's professional organization
- Implements email automation for new members with a validation interface for confirming new members
- Automatically adds new members to constant contact email list
- Accepts payments for membership dues with Stripe

Rust Discord Bot (2020)

https://github.com/jack-michaud/gl2n

- A bot that interacts with Discord's low level websocket API
- Written to be reliable (99% SLA) and configurable (through rule based DSL)
- Powers personal entertainment for chat room; manages Minecraft server, downloads videos, and performs reverse image searches on uploaded images.

Portfolio Site (2019)

https://github.com/jack-michaud/portfolio

- Personal portfolio https://portfolio.lomz.me
- JAMStack site built with Next.js
- Markdown blog posts statically rendered

PythonWebsocketRCE (2018)

https://github.com/jack-michaud/PythonWebsocketRCE

- Created a CLI for controlling captive JS and bash clients over a network.
- Designed an API for running distributed programs and for remotely executing code.